<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title type="text">Urban Grammar AI Blog</title>
  <id>https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/atom.xml</id>
  <updated>2021-04-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <link href="https://urbangrammarai.github.io/" />
  <link href="https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" />
  <generator uri="https://ablog.readthedocs.org" version="0.10.6">ABlog</generator>
  <entry xml:base="https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Second Advisory Board</title>
    <id>https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/post11_second_advisory_board.html</id>
    <updated>2021-04-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-04-29T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/post11_second_advisory_board.html" />
    <author>
      <name></name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On April 15th. 2021, we held the second meeting of the Advisory Board for the project. We are delighted that all &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/post3.html&quot;&gt;board members&lt;/a&gt; joined us on Zoom for a few hours of exciting discussions on the progress and the future of the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dani started with an overview of our progress since the last meeting, which you can check in his &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/post8_ubdc.html&quot;&gt;UBDC talk&lt;/a&gt;. We followed by the focused discussion on the concepts of Spatial Signature and Enclosed Tessellation and our initial paper illustrating both on the sample of cities worldwide. We discussed the clarity of our ideas and the needs for new spatial units and classification methods, and their potential drawbacks and enhancements. In the last part, we tried to zoom out to see a bigger picture and fit the research within existing projects within academia and the public sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After three hours of a very fruitful discussion, we finished with a lot of food for thought and ideas to be explored in the future. Let’s just hope that the Advisory Board meetings will soon happen physically in Liverpool to have an even more productive and friendly environment!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Clustergam: visualisation of cluster analysis</title>
    <id>https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/post10_clustergram.html</id>
    <updated>2021-04-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-04-27T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/post10_clustergram.html" />
    <author>
      <name></name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this post, we introduce a new Python package to generate clustergrams from clustering solutions. The library has been developed as part of the Urban Grammar project, and it is compatible with &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;scikit-learn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; and GPU-enabled libraries such as &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;cuML&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;cuDF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; within &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;RAPIDS.AI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we want to do some cluster analysis to identify groups in our data, we often use algorithms like K-Means, which require the specification of a number of clusters. But the issue is that we usually don’t know how many clusters there are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many methods on how to determine the correct number, like silhouettes or elbow plot, to name a few. But they usually don’t give much insight into what is happening between different options, so the numbers are a bit abstract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://www.schonlau.net/clustergram.html&quot;&gt;Matthias Schonlau&lt;/a&gt; proposed another approach - a clustergram. Clustergram is a two-dimensional plot capturing the flows of observations between classes as you add more clusters. It tells you how your data reshuffles and how good your splits are. &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.r-statistics.com/2010/06/clustergram-visualization-and-diagnostics-for-cluster-analysis-r-code/&quot;&gt;Tal Galili&lt;/a&gt; later implemented clustergram for K-Means in R. And I have used Tal’s
implementation, ported it to Python and created &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;clustergram&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; - a Python package to make clustergrams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;clustergram&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; currently supports K-Means and using &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;scikit-learn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; (inlcuding Mini-Batch implementation) and RAPIDS.AI &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;cuML&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; (if you have a CUDA-enabled GPU), Gaussian Mixture Model (&lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;scikit-learn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; only) and hierarchical clustering based on &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;scipy.hierarchy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;. Alternatively, we can create clustergram based on labels and data derived from alternative custom clustering algorithms. It provides a sklearn-like API and plots clustergram using matplotlib, which gives it a wide range of styling
options to match your publication style.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Spatial Signatures at the Spatial Analytics + Data Seminar Series</title>
    <id>https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/post9_sad.html</id>
    <updated>2021-04-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-04-26T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/post9_sad.html" />
    <author>
      <name></name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On March 30th, Martin presented the current progress in the development
of Spatial Signatures at the Spatial Analytics + Data Seminar Series
organised by the University of Newcastle, the University of Bristol and
the Alan Turing Institute. Martin presented the basics of urban morphometrics,
showing examples of relevant research based on the &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;momepy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; Python package to
provide a background for the second part of the talk focusing on Spatial
Signatures. The research was well received and initiated a great discussion,
which we hope will continue on some other platforms soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recording is available on Youtube:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The slides used are &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://urbangrammarai.github.io/talks/202103_sad/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or, if you prefer it, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://urbangrammarai.github.io/talks/202103_sad/index.pdf&quot;&gt;here is the &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; file&lt;/a&gt; (27Mb).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Spatial Signatures at UBDC</title>
    <id>https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/post8_ubdc.html</id>
    <updated>2021-04-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-04-08T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/post8_ubdc.html" />
    <author>
      <name></name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On March 16th, Dani presented ongoing work on the development of Spatial
Signatures at the University of Glasgow’s Urban Big Data Centre webinar
series. This was the first time we took the project on tour and it was very
well received. With an audience that peaked at about 75 folks and many great
questions that extended the session well over one hour, we are super happy
with how the foundational ideas of the project were received.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The link to the webinar, for posterity, is &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://ubdc.ac.uk/education-and-events/events-and-courses/past-events-2021/spatial-signatures-research-webinar/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and
you can have a look at an edited version of the video at:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The slides used are &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://urbangrammarai.github.io/talks/202103_ubdc&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or, if you prefer it, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://urbangrammarai.github.io/talks/202103_ubdc/index.pdf&quot;&gt;here is the &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; file&lt;/a&gt; (15Mb).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Visual style and a graphics package</title>
    <id>https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/post7_graphics.html</id>
    <updated>2021-02-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-17T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/post7_graphics.html" />
    <author>
      <name></name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Any work of the size of our Urban Grammar AI project has many outputs. All of them should ideally share the same design language, so once we combine them, they tell a coherent story. Therefore, we have defined a visual style applied to any graphical output we will produce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have started with a basic colourmap. A significant part of our work will result in categorical maps, so we need diverse colours. We have looked back at the excellent cartography our predecessors produced and found a gem. A study of wage and nationality in Chicago by Jane Addams and Florence Kelley from 1895 resulted in a series of beautiful maps like this one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hull House Maps and Papers (1895) by Jane Addams and Florence Kelley.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We based our primary colours on the six colours you can see on this map. This colour map offers a variety while retaining readability, colours nicely play with each other and, importantly, are colour blind safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Primary colours derived from Adams and Kelly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Contribution to tobler: Speeding up areal interpolation</title>
    <id>https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/post6_tobler.html</id>
    <updated>2021-02-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-16T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/post6_tobler.html" />
    <author>
      <name></name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Have you ever needed to link two sources of data, each attached to a different geometry? In our work in the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://urbangrammarai.github.io/spatial_signatures/index&quot;&gt;WP2&lt;/a&gt;, we do. We have to transfer data from various sources, linked to output areas, urban blocks or other spatial units to our own bespoke set of geographies. Therefore, we often need to do areal interpolation to correctly map data from one layer to another. Luckily, the open-source Python ecosystem can help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://pysal.org/tobler/&quot;&gt;Tobler&lt;/a&gt;, a part of &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://pysal.org&quot;&gt;PySAL family&lt;/a&gt;, is a library for areal interpolation and dasymetric mapping which already offered what we needed. However, our data tends to be large, up to 15 million rows on which we need to interpolate several hundreds of thousands of rows of input data. That can take a while, so each performance improvement can help a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have looked into the existing code of &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;tobler&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; and contributed to the refactoring if its &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;area_interpolate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; function. The original implementation was using custom code for spatial indexing, which was replaced by a performant vectorised implementation based on the more recent &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://pygeos.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;pygeos&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With sample data, we’ve been able to speed up the interpolation from 2.4 seconds to less than 400 milliseconds, having the same result 6x faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such an improvement is great, but it still uses only a single core (as most of the geospatial code to be honest), leaving the rest in a modern computer (four or more cores is not uncommon these days…) lazily laying around. We have tried to change this and contributed a (still experimental) parallel implementation of the same algorithm (based on &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://joblib.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;joblib&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">30DayMapChallenge 2020</title>
    <id>https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/post5_mapchallenge.html</id>
    <updated>2020-11-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2020-11-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/post5_mapchallenge.html" />
    <author>
      <name></name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On November 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; Topi Tjukanov &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tjukanov/status/1311568912950140930&quot;&gt;started&lt;/a&gt; a &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/30DayMapChallenge&quot;&gt;#30DayMapChallenge 2020&lt;/a&gt; - one day, one map, one theme. Because it is a lot of fun, the Geographic Data Science Lab wanted to be a part of it and on 23&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; day, it was our turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the topic was &lt;em&gt;boundaries&lt;/em&gt;, we decided to share with you the process of creation of boundaries of morpohlogical tessellation - the (smallest) spatial unit used in urban morphometrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five cities, five different urban patterns. Morphological tessellation is in principle Voronoi tessellation based on building footprint polygons. In practice, we first shrink our polygons (you need a gap between adjacent buildings) by a small margin, then generate a dense array of points along the polygon boundary which is passed to Voronoi algorithm. Finally, resulting polygons are dissolved based on the building it belongs to, and morphological tessellation is done. See by yourself how each step looks and compares across different patterns on a matrix below. If you click on the image, you can see the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/urbangrammarai/urbangrammarai.github.io/blob/mapchallenge/src/notebooks/mapchallenge/matrix_lowres.png?raw=true&quot;&gt;full resolution (16.2 MB)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you want to play with the algorithm and create your own sequences? We have a &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://nbviewer.jupyter.org/github/urbangrammarai/urbangrammarai.github.io/blob/mapchallenge/src/notebooks/mapchallenge/tessellation.ipynb&quot;&gt;notebook&lt;/a&gt; just for you! And if you’re going to generate tessellation on your data, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://docs.momepy.org/en/stable/user_guide/elements/tessellation.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;momepy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has you covered. For further details head to Martin’s blog post about &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://martinfleischmann.net/morphological-tessellation/&quot;&gt;a paper on tessellation&lt;/a&gt; he has published earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for new advances in this space!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Implementing morphological functions to the ecosystem</title>
    <id>https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/post4.html</id>
    <updated>2020-11-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2020-11-02T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/post4.html" />
    <author>
      <name></name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This blog post covers some of the efforts the team has made to contribute code developed for the project to the broader Python eco-system for (geographic) data science. Processing of data within &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://urbangrammarai.github.io/data_processing/index&quot;&gt;WP1&lt;/a&gt; and morphometric assessment within &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://urbangrammarai.github.io/spatial_signatures/index&quot;&gt;WP2&lt;/a&gt; entail the development of new bespoke algorithms and implementation of some which are currently available in the Python ecosystem. However, even those already existing were often not performant enough for the scale of this project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the data processing stage of the project, we have refactored some of them to gain the performance enhancements we needed. Since we strongly believe in replicability of research, all software developed within Urban Grammar AI project should be available for other researchers, optimally packaged in a friendly shape of a Python library. At the same time, we want to support open-source software which we use for the research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We think the natural approach is to include enhancements made within the area of urban morphometrics to &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://docs.momepy.org&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;momepy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; an existing toolkit for urban morphology. &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://urbangrammarai.github.io/spatial_signatures/index&quot;&gt;WP2&lt;/a&gt; heavily builds on &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;momepy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;’s code and every relevant piece of code we made is now merged back into &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;momepy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;. That covers both performance-focused changes to implementation (&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/martinfleis/momepy/pull/219&quot;&gt;#219&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/martinfleis/momepy/pull/209&quot;&gt;#209&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/martinfleis/momepy/pull/207&quot;&gt;#207&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/martinfleis/momepy/pull/205&quot;&gt;#205&lt;/a&gt;), mostly based on &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;pygeos&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; and vectorization, and new additions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two key features of Spatial Signatures, the concepts of &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://urbangrammarai.github.io/spatial_signatures/spatial_unit/Parallelized_enclosures.html&quot;&gt;enclosures&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://urbangrammarai.github.io/spatial_signatures/spatial_unit/enclosed_tessellation.html&quot;&gt;enclosed tessellation&lt;/a&gt; are now available in &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;momepy.elements&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; module and you can create both using only a few lines of code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the detailed guidance in &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://docs.momepy.org/en/latest/user_guide/elements/enclosed.html&quot;&gt;momepy’s documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">First Advisory Board</title>
    <id>https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/post3.html</id>
    <updated>2020-10-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2020-10-01T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/post3.html" />
    <author>
      <name></name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On October 1st. 2020, Dani and Martin held the first meeting of the Advisory Board for the project. We are thrilled to have a board that includes &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/edwardes/&quot;&gt;Alistair Edwardes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncl.ac.uk/curds/people/staffprofile/rachelfranklin.html#background&quot;&gt;Rachel Franklin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/izzysargent&quot;&gt;Isabel Sargent&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://www.dpi.inpe.br/DPI/institucional/pessoal/servidores/antonio-miguel-vieira-monteiro&quot;&gt;Antonio Miguel Vieira Monteiro&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting took place, as it’s become customary in 2020, on Zoom. Dani provided an overview of the main components of the project, and Martin updated on progress so far; throughout the three hours of the meeting, there was plenty of discussion and great questions about what the project is trying to do and how it’ll tackle its main challenges. This is by no means a full replacement of the physical meeting we would have had in Liverpool for a full day, but it was an excellent way to connect and kickstart the role of the Advisory Board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the conclusions from the discussion was that we might adapt to the current situation by trying to have these meetings a bit more frequent (initially only four were scheduled for the entire project) and of shorter duration than a full day (maybe up to three hours). This will allow us to focus on specific aspects of the project for every meeting. Next one will hopefully take place early in the next year and, by then, we might even have something in the form of deliverables to show!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Welcome to Martin Fleischmann</title>
    <id>https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/post2.html</id>
    <updated>2020-07-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2020-07-01T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/post2.html" />
    <author>
      <name></name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/urbangrammarai/urbangrammarai.github.io/blob/master/src/_static/martin.jpg?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Martin Fleischmann&quot; class=&quot;bg-primary&quot; width=&quot;200px&quot; style=&quot;float:left;margin-right: 10px;&quot;&gt; The project is thrilled to welcome Martin Fleischmann as the postdoctoral researcher who will work with me (Dani) for the next two years of the Fellowship. Here is a quick bio of Martin:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Martin Fleischmann is research associate in the Geographic Data Science Lab at the University of Liverpool and a member of the Urban Design Studies Unit at the University of Strathclyde. His research focuses on urban morphology and geographic data science focusing on quantitative analysis and classification of urban form, remote sensing and AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is the author of &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;momepy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;, the open source urban morphology measuring toolkit for Python and member of development teams of GeoPandas, the open source Python package for geographic data and PySAL, the Python library for spatial analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Martin brings with him a theoretical background in urban morphology combined with a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of experience in Python open source development around geospatial. There could not be a better combination for the project. As the postdoctoral researcher, Martin will be heavily involved in the implementation of much of the code required to develop the idea of Spatial Signatures, teach a computer to recognise them from satellite imagery, and use them to develop an Urban Grammar. At the same time, he is also joining the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.liverpool.ac.uk/geographic-data-science/&quot;&gt;Geographic Data Science Lab&lt;/a&gt; and getting involved in its day to day life, participating in internal seminars, coordinating the Brown Bags series and, more generally, chipping in where possible to make the lab a great place to be part of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome Martin, this will be a fun ride!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Firing up the engines</title>
    <id>https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/post1.html</id>
    <updated>2020-04-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2020-04-15T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://urbangrammarai.github.io/blog/post1.html" />
    <author>
      <name></name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the first post going out form the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.turing.ac.uk/research/research-projects/urban-grammar&quot;&gt;Urban Grammar project&lt;/a&gt;. We will use this blog to keep track of progress on the project and to announce milestones we are reaching along the way. If you are interested in cities, satellites and AI, keep an eye on the blog and feel free to get in touch with either &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;mailto:darribas-bel&amp;#37;&amp;#52;&amp;#48;turing&amp;#46;ac&amp;#46;uk&quot;&gt;Dani&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;mailto:M&amp;#46;Fleischmann&amp;#37;&amp;#52;&amp;#48;liverpool&amp;#46;ac&amp;#46;uk&quot;&gt;Martin&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
